Guide to the Carnochan Family Papers, 1745-1929
Department of Special Collections
Carnochan Family Papers,
1745-1929
Special Collections M849
Carnochan family Morris family Farnham family Lambard family Baldwin family Bliss family
11.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
None.
Provenance:
Gift of Bliss Carnochan, 1995 and 1996
SCOPE AND CONTENT
This collection contains Carnochan, Morris, Farnham, Lambard, Baldwin, and Bliss family papers and ephemera. Included are correspondence, documents (including commissions, maps, wills, bank statements, and receipts), printed material including bound genealogies and memorials, and photographs.
ADDED ENTRIES
Hayes, Rutherford B., 1822-1893; Stanton, Edwin McMasters, 1814-1869; Mott, Valentine, 1785-1865; Tweed, William Marcy, 1823-1878; Grant, Julia, 1826-1902; Sherman, William Tecumseh, 1820-1891; Morris, Lewis, 1671-1746; Morris, Gouverneur, 1752-1816; Morris, William Walton, 1802-1856; Morris, Mary Alexander Ritchie, 1815-1880; Morris, William Gouverneur, 1833-1884; Morris, Gouverneur William, 1841-1865; Morris, Arthur Breese, 1843-1892; Ramsey, Anne R. Morris, b. 1846; Carnochan, Estelle Morris, 1838-1922; Carnochan, John Murray, 1817-1887; Carnochan, Daisy; Carnochan, James; Carnochan, Gouverneur; Carnochan, Lillian; Carnochan, Mary; Morris, Sarah Caroline; Morris, William W.,Sr; Ritchie, Hester Alexander; Ritchie, Sally; Ritchie, Martha; Hasson, Alexander; Hasson, Hettie Ritchie; Little, Arabella; Little, A. Alexander; Stout, Aquila Giles; Stout, Anne Morris; Bliss, George; Baldwin, Henry Porter; Baldwin, Sibyl Lambard; Bliss, Katherine Baldwin; Lambard, Allen; Lambard, Sibyl Farnham; Lambard, Thomas; Lambard, Orville Dewey; Cobb, Phoebe Farnham; Farnham, John Hay
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence
  - Morris outgoing
    - A.M. Morris, June 24, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      1 letter A.M. Morris to M.A.M. June 24, 1857
    - Anne (Nan) Morris Ramsey, Mar. 4, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      1 letter A.M. to M.A.M. Mar. 4, 1857
    - Arthur Breese Morris, Sr. Mar. 26, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      1 letter A.B. Morris to M.A.M. Mar. 26, 1843
    - Arthur Breese Morris, Apr. 16, 1862-Jan. 13, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      2 letters A. M. to M.A.M. Apr. 16, 1862, Jan. 13, 1863
    - Gouverneur William Morris, Jan. 31, 1854-Feb. 22, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      7 letters G.W.M. to M.A.M. Jan. 31, 1854, July 27, 1857, July 16, 1861, Feb. 22, 1865; G.W.M. to E.M.C. Feb. 1856, Feb. 27, 1857; G.W.M. to A.M. Feb. 27, 1863
    - Gouverneur W. Morris, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      2 letters, n.d. (185-?); 1 fragment, n.d.: Civil War accounts; G.W.M. to M.A.M.
    - Gouverneur Morris, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      1 letter,1 genealogy and note G.M. to E.M.C., n.d.
    - James Morris, Aug. 27, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      1 letter and receipt J.M. to W.W.M. Aug. 27, 1825
    - John C. Morris, Oct. 9, 1840-Oct. 1, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      6 letters J.C.M. to cousin W.W.M. Oct. 9, 1840, July 1, 1845, July 30, 1845, Mar. 29, 1846, Oct. 1, 1846
    - John C. Morris and L.G. Morris, May 29, 1847-Oct. 7, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      4 letters J.C.M. to M.A.M. July 21, 1847, Aug. 25, 1847, Nov.13, 1847; J.C.M. to E.M. May 29, 1847
      L.G. Morris to E.M.C. Oct. 7, 1878
    - Mary Alexander Ritchie Morris, Jan. 22, 1833-Mar. 2, 1844 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      2 letters M.A.M. to W.W.M. Jan. 22, 1833; M.A.M. to W.G.M. Mar. 20, 1844
    - Mary A. Morris, May 13, 1845-Nov.29, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      3 letters, includes newsclipping on Thanksgiving turkeys, M.A.M. to W.W.M. May 13, 1845; M.A.M. to W.G.M. Aug. 14, 1845, Nov. 29, 1847
    - Mary A. Morris, May 12, 1848-May 30, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      3 letters M.A.M. to W.G.M. May 12, 1848, May 2, 1848, May 30, 1848
    - Mary A. Morris, July 26, 1848-Aug. 3, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      3 letters, 1 fragment, M.A.M. to W.G.M. July 26, 1848, July 30, 1848, Aug. 3, 1848
    - Mary A. Morris, July 8, 1850-June 3, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      3 letters M.A.M. to T. Casey July 8, 1850; M.A.M. to G.W.M. Apr. 24, 1854; M.A.M. to A.M. June 3, 1854
    - Mary A. Morris, Jan. 27, 1857-June 23, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      5 letters M.A.M. to A.M. Jan. 24, 1857; M.A.M. to E.M.C. Apr. 4, 1857, Dec. 5, 1857; M.A.M. to G.W.M. May 26, 1859, June 23, 1859
    - Mary A. Morris, May 4, 1861-May 9, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      3 letters M.A.M. to W.W.M. May 4, 1861, May 6, 1861, May 9, 1861
    - Mary A. Morris, May 22, 1861-Nov.15, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      3 letters M.A.M. to W.W.M. May 22, 1861; M.A.M. to G.W.M. and W.G.M. Nov.8, 1861; M.A.M. to W.G.M. Nov.15, 1861
    - Mary A. Morris, Apr. 10, 1865-Nov.29, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      5 letters M.A.M. to G.W.M Apr. 10, 1865, Oct. 8, 1865, Nov. 8, 1865, Nov. 25, 1865, [Nov.29, 1865]
    - Mary A. Morris, June 28, 1866-Aug. 3, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      2 letters M.A.M. to E.M.C. June 28, 1866, Aug. 3, 1867
    - Mary A. Morris, June 5, 1876-Feb. 28, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      6 letters M.A.M. to E.M.C. June 5, 1876, Dec. 2, 1876, Feb. 6, 1878, Oct. 22, 1878, Feb. 8, 1879; M.A.M. to "Nelly" Feb. 6, 1878
    - Mary A. Morris, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
      6 letters, n.d. [184-?], M.A.M. to W.G.M.
    - Mary A. Morris, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
      10 letters, n.d. [187-?] Per annotation, written near M.A.M.'s death (1880), M.A.M. to E.M.C.
    - Mary A. Morris, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
      4 letters, 1 fragment, n.d. M.A.M. to E.M.C.
    - Mary A. Morris, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
      1 letter, n.d. [1852?] M.A.M. to W.W.M.; 2 letters, n.d. M.A.M. to G.W.M.; 1 fragment
    - Mary A. Morris, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26)
      1 letter, n.d., M.A.M. to W.G.M [1848?]
    - Sarah Caroline Morris, Dec. 10, 1833-Aug. 1, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      2 letters S.C. Morris to W.W.M. Dec. 10, 1833; S.C.M. to M.A.M. Aug. 7, 1840
    - Sarah C. Morris, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      5 letters, n.d. [184-?], S.C.M. and A.M. Stout to M.A.M. and W.W.M.; S.C.M. to M.A.M. (4)
    - William Gouverneur Morris, Oct. 28, 1842-Mar. 7, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      3 letters W.G.M. to M.A.M. Oct. 29, 1842, Mar. 7, 1848; W.G.M. to W.W.M. Dec. 24, 1842
    - William G. Morris, July 29, 1852-July 6, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      4 letters W.G.M. to M.A.M. July 29, 1852, Dec. 15, 1852, July 19, 1854, July 6, 1855; Dec. 15, 1852 letter has note from M.A.M.
    - William G. Morris, July 8, 1867-Nov.20, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      2 letters, 1 n.d.; 4 fragments; W.G.M. to M.A.M. [July 8, 1867]; W.G.M. to E.M.C. Nov.14, 1883 and n.d. [184-?]
    - William Walton Morris, Sr., Sept. 28, 1824 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      1 letter W.W.M. Sr. to W.W.M. Sept. 28, 1824
    - William Walton Morris, Apr. 19, 1843-Sept. 2, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      3 letters W.W.M. to M.A.M. Apr. 19, 1843, Apr. 28, 1843, Sept. 2, 1845
    - William W. Morris, Feb. 25, 1847-July 7, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      3 letters W.W.M. to M.A.M. Feb. 25, 1847, May 19, 1847, July 7, 1847
    - William W. Morris, July 17, 1847-Nov.10, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      4 letters W.W.M. to M.A.M. July 17, 1847, Aug. 14, 1847, Oct. 22, 1847, Nov.10, 1847
    - William W. Morris, Oct. 23, 1849-June 27, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      5 letters W.W.M. to M.A.M. Oct. 23, 1849, Oct. 16, 1851, Feb. 24, 1852, May 11, 1852, June 27, 1852
    - William W. Morris, J an. 24, 1853-Oct. 3, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      5 letters W.W.M. to M.A.M. Jan. 24, 1853, Aug. 8, 1854, Oct. 3, 1854; W.W.M. to E.M.C. Jan. 11, 1854; W.W.M. to Bank of North Dec. 12, 1853
    - William W. Morris, Nov.4, 1855-Dec. 3, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      2 letters W.W.M. to M.A.M. Nov.4, 1855, Dec. 3, 1855
    - William W. Morris, Mar. 10, 1857-Nov.2, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      9 letters W.W.M. to M.A.M. Mar. 10, 1857, May 2, 1857, July 21, 1857, Aug. 6, 1857, Aug. 20, 1858, Nov.2, 1858; W.W.M. to E.M.C Mar. 24, 1857, Jan. 4, 1858; W.W.M. to S. Cooper Sept. 14, 1858
    - William W. Morris, Apr. 24, 1859-May 11, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      3 letters W.W.M. to M.A.M. Apr. 24, 1859, May 7, 1859, May 11, 1859
    - William W. Morris, Aug. 13, 1859-Aug. 22, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      2 letters W.W.M. to M.A.M. Aug. 13, 1859, Aug. 22, 1859
    - William W. Morris, Sept. 23, 1860 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      6 letters, 2 fragments W.W.M to W.F. Giles (with clipping) with W.F. Giles' response regarding habeas corpus May 6, 1861; W.W.M. to M.A.M. Sept. 23, 1860; W.W.M. to E.M.C. Nov.6, 1860, Dec. 30, 1860, Mar. 4, 1861
    - William W. Morris, Nov.1, 1863-June 22, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      3 letters W.W.M. to M.A.M. Nov.1, 1863, Nov.16, 1863, June 22, 1864 includes note to M.A.M. from Army officials
    - William W. Morris, July 17, 1864-Sept. 16, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      3 letters W.W.M. to M.A.M. July 17, 1864, Sept. 9, 1864, Sept. 16, 1864
    - William W. Morris, Mar. 12, 1865-May 9, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      2 letters W.W.M. to E.M.C. Mar. 12, 1865, May 9, 1865
    - William W. Morris, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 20)
      3 letters, n.d. Approx. Civil War era, W.W.M. to M.A.M.
    - William W. Morris, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21)
      8 letters, n.d. W.W.M. to M.A.M.
    - William W. Morris, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      1 love poem, n.d., W.W.M. to M.A.M.
    - William W. Morris (Box 2, Folder 23)
      1 typed summary of many W.W.M. letters, including brief biographical sketch. [Not all letters described in collection.]
  - Morris incoming
    - Henry M. Alexander, Oct. 18, 1867-Apr. 2, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      3 letters H.M. Alexander to M.A.M., Oct. 18, 1867, 2 n.d.
    - A----, Apr. 5, 1824-July 7, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      3 letters H. Atkinson to W.W.M. Apr. 5, 1824; J.A.Anderson to M.A.M., n.d.; Louis Aurch to M.A.M., July 7, 1865
    - Kate and William Baker, Aug., 18, 1841-Apr. 6, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      6 letters W. Baker to M.A.M., Aug. 16, 1841, Apr. 6, 1855; K. Stuart Baker to M.A.M., Dec. 30, 1842, Dec. 27, 1847, Nov. 25, 1850, June 2, 1852
    - B----, Aug. 25, 1824-Dec. 2, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      5 letters [Brally] to W.W.M. May 25, 1824; H.D.B. to M.A.M. Nov. 17, 1843; S. Bruce to M.A.M. Apr. 6, 1849; B. Bazett to M.A.M. June 19, 1853; L. P. Buell to M.A.M. Dec. 2, 1860
    - B-----, June 1875 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      5 letters, 3 n.d. G. Bell to A.B.M. June 15, 1875; W.W.Burns to A.B.M. June 20, 1875; [Isabelle Brooks] to M.A.M.; A.P. Banks to M.A.M.; H.D.B. to [M.A.M.]
    - Capt. T. Casey, Nov. 6, 1849-Sept. 12, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      8 letters, 1 n.d. T. Casey to E.M.C., Nov. 6, 1849, Dec. 3, 1849, May 1, 1850, Apr. 18, 1852; T. Casey. to M.A.M., Feb. 22, 1852, Feb. 1853, Sept. 12, 1857
    - E.M. Carpenter, Apr. 13, 1844 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      2 letters, 1 n.d. E.M. Carpenter to W.W.M. Apr. 13, 1844
    - Charles Clayton, Nov. 26, 1847-Aug. 9, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      3 letters, including note to James Clayton; C. Clayton to M.A.M. Nov. 26, 1847, Aug. 9, 1848; C. Clayton to J.Clayton, n.d.
    - C-----, Sept. 12, 1857-June 2, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      6 letters C. Cox to Dr. Reese June 14, 1860; C. Cox to M.A.M. Dec. 27, 1864; J. Chapman to W.W.M. June 2, 1864; M. S.R. Cougra to M.A.M., n.d. [Sept. 23, 1857?]; O. Cotten to P.A. Porter Nov. 25, 1863
    - D - E, Nov. 1, 1853-May 31, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      6 letters P. Durkee to M.A.M. Nov. 1, 1853 and n.d.; J. Dix to M.A.M. Oct. 25, 1861; M.A. Dornier to "Commanding Officers of any of our vessels..." Dec. 4, 1863; E. Driffenduser to G.W.M. Feb. 22, 1865; A.R. Eddy to A.B.M. May 31, 1875
    - F-----, Sept. 23, 1843-July 18, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      3 letters W.G. Freeman to M.A.M. Sept. 23, 1843; W.G. Freeman to W.W.M. Mar. 2, 1854; T.Y. Field to W.W.M. July 18, 1864
    - Caroline Gardner, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 12)
      5 letters C. Gardner to M.A.M., n.d.
    - Caroline Gardner, nd. (Box 3, Folder 13)
      4 letters C. Gardner to M.A.M. n.d.; 1 tombstone inscription for John Henry Gardner
    - G-----, Jan. 1, 1827-Oct. 9, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      2 letters E.P. Gaines to W.W.M. Jan. 1, 1827; Julia Grant to M.A.M. Oct. 9, 1872
    - Alexander Hasson, Feb. 10, 1858-July 12, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      3 letters A. Hasson to M.A.M., Feb. 10, 1858, Feb. 15, 1858, July 12, 1865
    - Hettie Ritchie Hasson, nd. (Box 3, Folder 16)
      5 letters, n.d. [184?-185?] H. Hasson to M.A.M.
    - H-I, June 13, 1859-Oct. 26, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      6 letters J. Herford to M.A.M. June 13, 1859; T.H. Hicks to W.W.M. June 28, 1864; M. Hogan to W.G.M. Oct. 26, 1866; T. P. Ives to M.A.M. Apr. 2, 1863, Apr. 10, 1863, May 10, 1864
    - J-----, Aug. 29, 1840-Feb. 11, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      2 letters A.M. Jones to W.W.M. Aug. 29, 1840; A.M. Jones to M.A.M. Apr. 29, 1845; R. Johnson to -Feb. 11, 1867
    - [I.] Lehner, Apr. 3, 1845 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      1 letter T. Lehner to W.W.M. Apr. 3, 1845
    - A. Alexander Little, Nov. 23, 1869-Nov. 26, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      2 letters A.A. Little to M.A.M. Nov. 23, 1869, Nov. 26, 1869
    - Arabella Alexander Little, Sept. 13, 1843-Sept. 23, 1856 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      4 letters, 1 n.d. A. Little to M.A.M., Sept. 13, 1843, Sept. 23, 1856, n.d.; A. Little to H.A.R., Jan. 28, 1852
    - William Little, Sept. 21, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      1 letter W. Little to M.A.M., Sept. 21, 1859
    - J.K. Mitchell, June 26, 1862 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      1 letter J.K. Mitchell to E.M. Stanton June 26, 1862
    - M-----, Mar. 9, 1827-Jan. 16, 1844 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      2 letters Philip [Mines] to Thomas Laul Mar. 9, 1827; J.P. McCour to W.W.M. Jan. 16, 1844
    - N - P, Jan. 20, 1848-Apr. 5, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      7 letters [James Pergase] to M.A.M. Jan. 20, 1848; J. Parker to W.W.M. Jan. 23, 1855, Sept. 15, 1856, Oct. 30, 1856; P.A. Porter to M.A.M. 3, 18, 1864; [Marcia Ross Neill] to M.A.M. May 16, 1864; C. Parker to M.A.M. Apr. 5, 1869
    - A. A. Ritchie, June 26, 1842-Oct. 8, 1847 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      4 letters A.A.R. to M.A.M., June 26, 1842, Apr. 28, 1845; A.A.R. to W.W.M., Apr. 26, 1845; A.A.R. to W.G.M. ,Oct. 8, 1847
    - Hester Alexander Ritchie, Nov. 3, 1839-Apr. 17, 1851 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      10 letters H.A.R. to M.A.M., [Nov. 3, 1839], Mar. 12, 1847, Apr. 16, 1847, Aug. 23, 1848, Dec. 22, 1848, Apr. 8, 1849, June 6, 1849, May 19, 1850, Feb. 24, 1859, Apr. 17, 1851
    - Hester A. Ritchie, Feb. 23, 1852-Oct. 9, 1853 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      9 letters H.A.R. to M.A.M., Feb. 23, 1852, Apr. 6, 1852, Apr. 25, 1852, Feb. 9, 1853, Apr. 17,1853, Sept. 19, 1853, July 13, 1853, July 31, 1853, Oct. 9, 1853
    - Hester A. Ritchie, May 2, 1854-Oct. 17, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      6 letters H.A.R. to M.A.M., May 2, 1854, May 16, 1854, Nov. 27, 1854, Dec. 24, 1854, Sept. 4, 1855, Oct. 17, 1855
    - Hester A. Ritchie, Feb. 9, 1857-Mar. 27, 1859 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      5 letters H.A.R. to M.A.M., Feb. 9, 1857, Mar. 31, 1857, July 10, 1857, Feb. 9, 1859
    - Hester A. Ritchie, Feb. 16, 1860-Apr. 14, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      7 letters H.A.R. to M.A.M., Feb. 16, 1860, Apr. 8, 1860, May 14, 1860, June 19, 1860, Jan. 28, 1861, Mar. 10, 1861, Apr. 14, 1861
    - Hester A. Ritchie, May 5, 1861-May 27, 1866 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      11 letters H.A.R. to M.A.M., May 5, 1861, May 23, 1861, July 17, 1861, Aug. 22, 1861, Oct. 22, 1861, Oct. 30, 1861, Jan. 8, 1862, Feb. 1, 1862, Oct. 23, 1864, May 27, 1866
    - Martha Ritchie, Nov. 24, 1874 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      1 letter M.R. to M.A.M., Nov. 24, 1874
    - Sally Ritchie, 1840 and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
      5 letters S.R. to M.A.M., 3 n.d.; S.R. to W.W.M., [Nov. 5, 1840], Nov. 10, 1840
    - Sally Ritchie, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 10)
      3 letters S.R. to M.A.M., n.d.
    - R.C. Rogers, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 11)
      1 letter, n.d. R.C. Rogers to "Patsie"
    - Isabella Rutherford, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 12)
      4 letters, n.d. I. Rutherford to M.A.M.
    - Rutherford, May 9, 1848-Sept. 10, 1856 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      3 letters L. Rutherford to M.A.M. Sept. 10, 1856; S. Rutherford to M.A.M. June 23, 1856; W. Rutherford to W.G.M. May 9, 1848
    - Arabella Ritchie Scott, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 14)
      5 letters, n.d. [1 identified Nov. 3, 1839] A.J. Scott to her sister M.A.M.
    - Fanny and Hugh Scott, Oct. 2, 1847 and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 15)
      2 letters H. Scott to sister-in-law M.A.M. Oct. 2, 1847; F. Scott to aunt M.A.M., n.d.
    - Frances Ritchie Shepard, May 4, 1847-June 2, 1850 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      2 letters F. R. Shepard to M.A.M., May 4, 1847, June 2, 1850
    - William Tecumseh Sherman, May 20, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      W.T. Sherman to W.W.M. May 20, 1861
    - Aquila Giles Stout, Feb. 6, 1843-June 11, 1851 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      5 letters A.G. Stout to brother-in-law W.W.M., Feb. 6, 1843. Nov. 11, 1843, June 11, 1851, n.d.; A.G. Stout to sister-in-law M.A.M., Oct. 14, 1846
    - Anne Morris Stout, July 11, 1843 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      5 letters A.M. Stout to nephew W.G.M., July 11, 1843; A.M. Stout to brother W.W.M. Jan. 12, 1845, May 6, 1861; A.M. Stout to sister-in-law M.A.M., n.d. (2)
    - S-----, Dec. 15, 1843-Aug. 20, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      4 letters R. Sterling to W.W.M. Dec. 18, 1843; E.E. Stuart to M.A.M. Aug. 26, 1854; E. Smith to M.A.M. June 1, 1863; Sprague to W.W.M. May 21, 1863; D.L. Simpson to aunt M.A.M. Aug. 20, 1867
    - L. Thompson, May 17, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      1 letter L. Thompson to M.A.M. May 17, 1855
    - Williams, Feb. 2, 1842-June 19, 1842 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      2 letters Williams to M.A.M. Feb. 22, 1842, June 19, 1842
    - W-----, Jan. 3, 1852-June 1, 1875 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      6 letters, 3 cards B. Wheeler to N.M. Jan. 3, 1852; H.B. Whipple to M.A.M. Dec. 4, 1862; R. Williams to M.A.M. Dec. 20, 1862; R. Williams to W.W.M. Jan. 10, 1863; G. Welles to G.W.M. June 23, 1864; S. Wilson to A.B.M. June 1, 1875; Williamson to G.W.M. n.d. 3 cards (wedding invitation)
    - Unknown (Box 4, Folder 24)
      7 letters
  - Carnochan outgoing
    - Daisy Carnochan, Aug. 5, 1886 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      1 letter D.C. to J.M.C. Aug. May [1886]
    - Estelle Morris Carnochan, May 4, 1850-July 27, 1850 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      4 letters E.M.C. to M.A.M. May 4, 1850, June 14, 1850, June 29, 1850, July 27, 1850
    - Estelle M. Carnochan, Jan. 27, 1854 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      3 letters E.M. to M.A.M. Jan. 27, 1854, Apr. 24, 1854, -/20, 1854
    - Estelle M. Carnochan, June 13, 1857-Aug. 1, 1858 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      5 letters E.M.C. to M.A.M. June 13, 1857, Mar. 2, 1857, Aug. 8, 1857, 4, 18, 1858, Aug. 1, 1858
    - Estelle M. Carnochan, Aug. 21, 1859-Dec. 5, 1859 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      3 letters E.M.C. to M.A.M. Aug. 21, 1859, Nov. 21, 1859, Dec. 5, 1859
    - Estelle M. Carnochan, Oct. 15, 1861-Mar. 28, 1863 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      3 letters E.M.C. to M.A.M. Oct. 15, 1861, 3, 18, 1863, Mar. 28, 1863
    - Estelle M. Carnochan, Apr. 10, 1863-Apr. 20, 1863 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      4 letters E.M.C. to M.A.M. Apr. 10, 1863, Apr. 13, 1863, Apr. 16, 1863, Apr. 20, 1863
    - Estelle M. Carnochan, May 27, 1863-July 21, 1872 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      3 letters E.M.C. to M.A.M. May 27, 1868, Oct. 7, 1863; E.M.C. to A.M.R. July 21, 1872
    - Estelle M. Carnochan, Aug. 30, 1887-May 2, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      2 letters E.M.C. to J.M.C. Aug. 30, 1887; E.M.C. to Gen. Sherman May 2, 1888 (copy)
    - Estelle M. Carnochan, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      9 letters, 1 fragment, 1 sketch (by E.M.C.?) E.M.C. to M.A.M.; E.M.C. to W.W.M.; E.M.C. to A.M.R.
    - James Carnochan, May 10, 1859 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      J.C. to J.M.C. May 10, 1859
    - John Murray Carnochan, Sept. 8, 1862-Apr. 22, 1870 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      7 letters J.M.C. to E.M.C. Sept. 8, 1862, Mar. 3, 1863; J.M.C. to Alonzo White Apr. 22, 1868, 6, 18, 1868 (copy); J.M.C. to Robert Mure Apr. 23, 1868 (copy); J.M.C. to John Ring 5, 18, 1868 (copy); J.M.C. to Sen. Frost Apr. 22, 1870
    - John M. Carnochan, 1861-1865 and n.d. (Box 5, Folder 13)
      4 letters, n.d. 2 letters annotated 1861; 1 letter written from Civil War front; 1 letter annotated 1865
    - Mary Carnochan, July 31, 1854 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      M.C. to her nephew J.M.C. July 31, 1854
    - [Mami] Carnochan, Apr. 8, 1872 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      1 letter M.C. to E.M.C. Apr. 5, 1872
  - Carnochan incoming
    - A-----, Mar. 14, 1854-June 16, 1871 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      W. Adams to J.M.C. Aug. 3, 1854; M. Anker to J.M.C. June 16, 1871; Dr. Auzias-Turenne Mar. 14, 1854, Feb. 8, 1866, n.d.
    - B-----, Aug. 13, 1864-Oct. 31, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      8 letters J. Barlow to E.M.C.Aug. 13, 1864; H. Bergh to J.M.C. 6, 1876; A.C. Bettner to E.M.C. Oct. 8, 1866, Dec. 30, 1875; A.C. Bettner to J.M.C. Sept. 15, 1886; [J.G. Beunett] to E.M.C., n.d.; T. Brignoi to J.M.C. Aug. 27, 1879; Beaufort to Col. Buck Oct. 31, 1881
    - C-----, Nov. 17, 1856-Apr. 24, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      6 letters H.M. Castelnau to J.M.C. Nov. 17, 1856; ---to H.Cox Aug. 10, 1860; C. Cutler to J.M.C. Dec. 2, 1884 includes letter from A.L. Labriskie to Senator Frye Nov. 12, 1884; L. Crosby to Gouverneur Carnochan n.d. [Apr. 24, 1929]; L. Crosby to H.W. Kent (Secretary at Metropolitin Museum of Art) Apr. 24, 1929
    - D - G, Feb. 17, 1848-Dec. 29, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      6 letters H. DeWees to J.M.C. June 24, 1860; J. Duncan to E.M.C., n.d. (1854 per annotation); Comte de Dion to J.M.C. Dec. 29, 1881; G. Gordon to J.M.C. Feb. 17, 1848
    - H-----, Dec. 6, 1870-July 3, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      9 letters W.S. Hancock to J.M.C. July 5, 1880; Harper and Brothers to J.M.C. Feb. 14, 1878 (2), Feb. 20, 1878, July 3, 1888; Health Department to J.M.C. Dec. 6, 1870, Apr. 21, 1879; E. Hodder to J.M.C. Oct. 30, 1863; C. Hulse to E.M.C. Apr. 19, 1887
    - J - K, Mar. 26, 1866-May 20, 1885 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      3 letters C. Jackson to J.M.C. May 20, 1885; E. Kean to J.M.C. Mar. 26, 1866, June 23, 1866
    - L-----, Nov. 4, 1882-May 11, 1884 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      2 letters T. Ludlow to his uncle J.M.C. May 11, 1884; [P.Lan-] to J.M.C. Nov. 4, 1882
    - Mc-----, Apr. 21, 1860-June 8, 1886 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      5 letters D. MacLeod to J.M.C. June 8, 1886; Gen. McMahon to J.M.C. Aug. 2, 1868; W.D. McMillan to J.M.C. Sept. 28, 1860, July 29, 1870, n.d. [Apr. 21, 1860]
    - M-----, June 11, 1866-Mar. 15, 1872 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      4 letters J.C. Minor to J.M.C. May 24, 1870; A. Moore to J.M.C. June 11, 1866; J. Mullaly to E.M.C. Mar. 15, 1872; Senator [Murrell] Apr. 19, 1871
    - Valentine Mott, Jan. 27, 1834-May 1, 1858 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      7 letters V. Mott to J.M.C. Jan. 27, 1834, Nov. 14, 1838, Apr. 30, 1844, May 1, 1858; Includes 3 n.d., illustration of J.M.C. and business card
    - Robert Mure, Sept. 18, 1843-June 24, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      7 letters R. Mure to J.M.C. 9, 18, 1843, July 16, 1844, Jan. 23, 1846, Jan. 16, 1847, Mar. 31, 1847, June 14, 1847, June 24, 1847
    - Robert Mure, Jan. 24, 1849-June 12, 1860 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      8 letters R. Mure to J.M.C. Jan. 24, 1849, Nov. 15, 1849, Jan. 26, 1856, Jan. 7, 1857, Mar. 6, 1857, July 2, 1859, Sept. 25, 1860, June 12, 1860
    - Robert Mure, Apr. 5, 1861-July 22, 1861 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      5 letters R. Mure to J.M.C. Apr. 5, 1861 (3), July 6, 1861, July 22, 1861
    - Robert Mure, June 11, 1866-Apr. 25, 1870 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      9 letters R. Mure to J.M.C. June 11, 1866, June 22, 1866, Nov. 11, 1866, Apr. 9, 1867, Apr. 28, 1868, June 8, 1868, July 11, 1868, Apr. 23, 1870; R. Mure to A. White Apr. 3, 1868
    - New York offices, Aug. 1, 1860-Jan. 28, 1870 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      2 letters Board of Commissioners of Emgigration Aug. 1, 1860; New York Executive Chamber to J.M.C. Jan. 28, 1870
    - O - P, Aug. 5, 1865-Sept. 12, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      3 letters C.L. O'Conor to J.M.C. Aug. 3, 1865; J. Paget to J.M.C. Sept. 12, 1881; Parker to J.M.C. Nov. 13, 1857